<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Predictor" icon="lns.png">
	<name>Local Novelty Scorer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Scores the novelty of test instances based on a local KNFST model trained with the k nearest neighbors in kernel space.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node calculates a local KNFST-model based on the nearest neighbors in the kernel space
			 for every single data point that is to be tested.
			 The corresponding source code is a Java adaption of the Matlab code provided by Bodesheim et al.
			 for their paper "Local Novelty Detection in Multi-class Recognition Problems".
		</intro>
		<tab name="Options">

			<option name="Training Columns"> The columns which should be used for training
			(right now only numeric columns can be used for training)
			</option>

			<option name="Class Column"> The column containing the class of the training samples
			</option>
			<option name="Kernel">
				Choose the Kernel that should be used
				<ul>
					<li>HIK - Histogram intersection kernel</li>
					<li>EXPHIK - Exponential variant of the HIK</li>
					<li>RBF - Radial basis function kernel (with parameter sigma)</li>
					<li>Polynomial - Polynomial kernel (with parameters gamma, bias and power)</li>
				</ul>
			</option>
			<option name="Number of Neighbors"> 
				Select the number of neighbors that should be used for training the local models.
			</option>
			<option name="Normalize Novelty Scores">
				Check to normalize the Novelty Scores by the minimum distance between target points.
			</option>
			<option name="Sort Training Table">
				Check to sort training table by class prior to calculation of the local models.
				Only use if training table is not already sorted by class.
			</option>			
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="KNFST model">KNFST model
		</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="Test Data">Test Data</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Novelty Scores">Novelty Scores</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>