<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="nodepotential.png" type="Predictor"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">

	<name>Density Scorer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Calculates density scores given a density model.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Calculates density scores for the input table given a density model.
			Note that the model can only be applied to the data it was initialized with in the corresponding initializer node (<b>Potential Density Initializer</b> or <b>Graph Density Initializer</b>).
			If the optional second input table with newly labeled data is connected, the model is updated before the scores are calculated.
			The update is performed by reducing the densities in the neighborhoods of all newly labeled data points according to the used density estimation algorithm.
		</intro>
		<option name="Output Column Name">Name of the appended density score column.
		</option>
		<option name="Unknown Row Handling">There are two ways to deal with unknown rows. The first applies to both the scoring as well as the update and simply fails whenever an unknown row is encountered.
		The second strategy is to ignore unknown rows in either of the input table. For the rows a density score is assigned to this means that an unknown row gets a missing value as density score.
		In case a row from the optional second input table is missing, it will simply be skipped during the update process.</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Density Scorer Model" index="0">Density scorer model created with either the <b>Potential Density Initializer</b> or the <b>Graph Density Initializer</b> node.
		</inPort>
		<inPort name="Scoring Data" index="1">Table containing rows for which the current density score is required. 
		</inPort>
		<inPort name="Update Data" index="2" optional="true">
		Table containing rows whose density in the model needs to be reduced prior to scoring the first input table.
		In an active learning setting these would be the rows that were freshly labeled by the user.
		The update is omitted if this port is not connected.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Updated Density Scorer Model" index="0">The updated
			model i.e. decreased densities in the neighborhood of
			rows in the second input table.</outPort>
		<outPort name="Density Score Table" index="1">The input table with
			an appended density score column. The name of the column can be
			specified via the Output Column Name option.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>