<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="labelModelIcon.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.12"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.12 http://knime.org/node/v2.12.xsd">

	<name>Label Model</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Estimates probabilistic labels by learning a generative label model from the provided noisy label sources.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Estimates probabilistic labels by learning a generative label
			model
			from the provided noisy labels.
			This node is a key component for the
			realization of weak supervision approaches as popularized by
			<a href="https://hazyresearch.github.io/snorkel/">Snorkel</a>
			.
			The idea in weak supervision is that it is often possible to create
			a number of simple inaccurate models (e.g. simple rules or existing
			models for slightly different tasks) that can label unlabeled data
			and that the agreements and disagreements of these simple models can
			be analyzed to infer information of the true label.
			Our implementation
			is a TensorFlow based adaptation of the matrix completion approach
			proposed in
			this
			<a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1810.02840.pdf">paper</a>
			by the Snorkel team.
			We refer to the publication for details on the
			strategy.
		</intro>
		<option name="Label sources">
			Select the columns which act as label sources i.e.
			that contain noisy
			labels for some in the rows in the first input
			table.
			It is assumed
			that a missing value means that the respective
			label source did not
			label the corresponding row.
		</option>
		<option name="Epochs">
			The number of optimization steps to perform. More
			epochs can result in better results but also directly translate into
			a longer runtime.
		</option>
		<option name="Learning rate">
			The learning rate dictates how much a single
			training epoch changes the learned model. A smaller learning rate
			requires more epochs to reach convergence
			while a large learning rate
			might lead divergence of the algorithm.
		</option>
		<option name="Label column name">
			The name of the label (or class) column that the
			labels provided by the label sources belong to.
			This value is used to
			create the column names for the probability columns in the output.
		</option>
		<option name="Remove source columns">
			Select if you want to remove the label source
			columns from the output table.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Label Sources" index="0">Table containing label
			sources. A label source is just a nominal column. Note that missing
			values in a label source are interpreted as abstains i.e. it is
			assumed that a missing value indicates that the label source did
			decide not to label the corresponding row. Label sources without a
			set of possible values assigned are ignored during the computation
			and a corresponding warning is displayed on the node.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Probabilistic Labels" index="0">Contains for each
			row in the input additional probabilistic label columns. That is for
			each of the possible classes, a column which gives the probability
			that a row is an instance of that class.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Source Statistics" index="1">
			Each row in
			this table gives the conditional probabilities
			that the
			label source displayed in the
			<i>Label Source</i>
			column takes on a specific value given the true label
			displayed in the
			<i>Latent Label</i>
			column.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>