<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./labeling.png" type="Visualizer" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
    <name>Labeling View</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
    	This node allows the user to manually assign labels to objects.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
    		This node allows the user to manually assign labels to objects. This is useful to e.g. create training data for learning algorithms
    		or create a ground-truth to test your algorithms etc. New labels can be created, renamed or deleted freely. <b>NOTE: "?" is a
    		reserved label and cannot be added. Exsiting labels of "?" will be replaced as Missing Values in the output table.</b>
		</intro>
        <tab name="Labeling">
            <description>
                General labeling options.
            </description>
            <option name="Column with possible labels">
                Possible domain values of the selected column get used as label classes.
            </option>
            <option name="Ignore existing labels">
                If this option is selected, the labels from the column chosen for the "Column with possible labels" column
                are ignored and the view will only use the nominal values in the domain of that column for initializing the
                available labels in the view (as buttons). This means it will not take the existing values for each row as there label value.
                If left unchecked, the node will use the existing labels (except for missing values) as labels for the rows.
            </option>
             <option name="Add new labels in View">
                When this option is enabled it is possible to add/delete labels when the view is opened.
                For this, there will be an extra option in the view menu when this option is set.
            </option>
            <option name="Show progress bar at the top of the view">
                When this option is set, there will be a progress bar in the view, which shows the progress of the labeling.
            </option>
            <option name="Automatically select next tile when tiles are labeled">
                When this option is set, the next tile will be automatically be selected after one of the label buttons was pressed.
                Rightmost selected tile is at the last position of the page, the next page will be displayed and the first tile on that page will be selected.
            </option>
            <option name="Append new column">
                When this options is selected the output of the labeling will be appended in a new column with the given name.
            </option>
            <option name="Replace existing column">
                When this options is selected the output of the labeling will replace the given column.
            </option>
            
        </tab>
		<tab name="Options">
            <description>
                General view and display options.
            </description>
            <option name="No. of rows to display">
                Use this numerical value to restrict the number of rows used for this visualization.
            </option>
            <option name="Title" optional="true">
                An optional title to be displayed above the tiles. Leave blank if no title is desired.
            </option>
            <option name="Subtitle" optional="true">
                An optional subtitle to be displayed above the tiles. Leave blank if no subtitle is desired.
            </option>
            <option name="Fixed number of tiles per row (1-100)">
                If checked, the specified number of tiles will be displayed for each row. The number of tiles per row 
                must be between 1 and 100, inclusive. The width of these tiles will change as the window size changes, 
                unless "Fixed tile width" is selected (see below).
            </option>
            <option name="Fixed tile width (30-5000px)">
                If checked, each tile will have the specified width. The specified width must be between 30px and 
                5000px, inclusive. The number of tiles per row will vary with the window size, unless "Fixed number 
                of tiles per row" is selected (see above).
            </option>
            <option name="Select text alignment">
                The alignment of the text within each tile.
            </option>
            <option name="Columns to display">
                Select the columns whose contents should be included in the tile’s contents.
            </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Interactivity">
            <description>
                The JavaScript Labeling View allows for several ways of interactivity. Please use the options below to
                configure which features will be activated on the view and further configuration of interactive
                properties.
            </description>
            <option name="Initial page size">
                Set the page size to be used on initial layout. A page size is defined as the number of tiles the view
                displays on one page. If the page size change control is enabled the page length can be changed in the
                view.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable page size change control">
                Enable or disable the control to change the page size interactively in the view.
            </option>
            <option name="Selectable page sizes">
                Define a comma-separated list of allowed page sizes for the page size control.
            </option>
            <option name="Add 'All' option to page sizes">
                When checked, an additional 'All' option will be available in the page size control.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable selection">
                If checked a checkbox is rendered in the bottom left corner of each tile. The selection, when applied,
                will be represented in the output table as a new boolean column.
            </option>
            <option name="Subscribe to filter events">
                If checked, the view reacts when applied filters have been changed.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable 'Clear Selection' button">
                If checked a button is displayed above the tiles, to clear any selection that is applied, regardless of
                current search and/or filter settings.
            </option>
            <option name="Show selected tiles only">
                If checked, only tiles which are selected are displayed.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable 'Show selected tiles only' option">
                If checked, a checkbox to switch on and off the mode of displaying only selected tiles is rendered in 
                the view.
            </option>
            <option name="Publish selection events">
                If checked, notifies other interactive views when user changes the selection in the current view. See
                also "Subscribe to selection events".
            </option>
            <option name="Subscribe to selection events">
                If checked, the view reacts on notifications from other interactive views that the selection has been
                changed. See also "Publish selection events".
            </option>
        </tab>
        
<tab name="Formatters">
            <description>
                The JavaScript Labeling View maps the KNIME table data types to types in JavaScript. The types that can be
                displayed are:
                <ul>
                    <li>Boolean</li>
                    <li>Number (double, integer, etc.)</li>
                    <li>String</li>
                    <li>Date and Time (legacy)</li>
                    <li>Zoned Date and Time</li>
                    <li>Local Date and Time</li>
                    <li>Local Date</li>
                    <li>Local Time</li>
                    <li>PNG</li>
                    <li>SVG</li>
                </ul>
                All other data types will be treated as UNKNOWN types. The node tries to display them by extracting
                their respective standard string representation.
                <br />
                <br />
                If you wish to customize the format for certain data types you can use the following options. For
                unknown types the formatting has to be applied in preceding nodes.
                <br />
                <br />

                <b>Date and Time types</b>
                Date and Time values are converted into string using the selected or entered conversion pattern as
                defined by <a href="http://momentjs.com/docs/#/displaying/format/">moment.js</a>. Examples:
                <ul>
                    <li>"dddd, MMMM Do YYYY, h:mm:ss a" formats dates like "Sunday, February 14th 2010, 3:25:50 pm"
                    </li>
                    <li>"ddd, hA" formats dates like "Sun, 3PM"</li>
                    <li>
                        "YYYY-MM-DDTHH:mm:ssZ" formats dates as defined by
                        <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO_8601">ISO 8601</a>.
                    </li>
                </ul>
                Some valid pattern elements are:
                <ul>
                    <li>Y: year</li>
                    <li>Q: quarter</li>
                    <li>M: month of year</li>
                    <li>W: week of year</li>
                    <li>DDD: day of year</li>
                    <li>D: day of month</li>
                    <li>d: day of week</li>
                    <li>dd: day of week (Su Mo ... Fr Sa)</li>
                    <li>a: am/pm marker</li>
                    <li>H: hour in day (0-23)</li>
                    <li>k: hour in day (1-24)</li>
                    <li>h: hour in am/pm (1-12)</li>
                    <li>m: minute in hour</li>
                    <li>s: second in minute</li>
                    <li>S: millisecond</li>
                    <li>z: Time zone (EST CST ... MST PST)</li>
                    <li>Z: Time zone (offset)</li>
                    <li>X: unix timestamp</li>
                </ul>
                Localized formats:
                <ul>
                    <li>LT: Time (e.g. 8:30 PM)</li>
                    <li>LTS: Time with seconds (e.g. 8:30:25 PM)</li>
                    <li>L: Month numeral (0 padded), day of month (0 padded), year (e.g. 09/04/1986)</li>
                    <li>l: Month numeral, day of month, year (e.g. 9/4/1986)</li>
                    <li>LL: Month name, day of month, year (e.g. September 4 1986)</li>
                    <li>ll: Month name (short), day of month, year (e.g. Sep 4 1986)</li>
                    <li>LLL: Month name, day of month, year, time (e.g. September 4 1986 8:30 PM)</li>
                    <li>lll: Month name (short), day of month, year, time (e.g. Sep 4 1986 8:30 PM)</li>
                    <li>LLLL: Month name, day of month, day of week, year, time
                        (e.g. Thursday, September 4 1986 8:30 PM)
                    </li>
                    <li>llll: Month name (short), day of month, day of week (short), year, time
                        (e.g. Thu, Sep 4 1986 8:30 PM)
                    </li>
                </ul>
                For printing an arbitrary string, wrap the string in square brackets, e.g. '[today] dddd'.
            </description>
            <option name="Locale">
                The locale which is used to render all date/time cells.
            </option>
            <option name="Local Date format">
                A global format, which is applied to all locale date cells. To format the string the framework moment.js
                is used.
            </option>
            <option name="Local Date &amp; Time format">
                A global format, which is applied to all local date/time cells. To format the string the framework
                moment.js is used.
            </option>
            <option name="Local Time format">
                A global format, which is applied to all local time cells. To format the string the framework moment.js
                is used.
            </option>
            <option name="Zoned Date &amp; Time format">
                A global format, which is applied to all zoned date/time cells. To format the string the framework
                moment.js is used.
            </option>
            <option name="Date &amp; Time (legacy) format">
                A global format, which is applied to all date/time (legacy) cells. To format the string the framework
                moment.js is used.
            </option>
            <option name="Enable global number format (double cells)">
                If checked the option beneath will be applied to all columns of type <i>Double</i>.
            </option>
            <option name="Decimal places">
                If number format is enabled use this value to restrict the display of decimal places for double columns
                in the tile view.
            </option>
            <option name="Display missing value as red question mark">
                If checked, a missing value in the tile view is represented by a red question mark. Otherwise, an empty
                cell is shown.
            </option>
        </tab>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <interactiveView name="Labeling View">
		Displays the detail of the current object to annotate.
	</interactiveView>
	
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Data" index="0">Table</inPort>
		<outPort name="Annotated data" index="0">Annotated table</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
