<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="nodepotentialscorer.png" type="Learner"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">

	<name>Potential Density Initializer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Initializes a density based exploration potential of a n-dimensional vector space.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Creates a potential based density model of a
			n-dimensional vector space.
			<br />
			In order to calculate the density at a specific row in the table, its immediate neighborhood in the vector space is considered.
			The closer and more numerous the neighbors the higher is the density.
			The size of the neighborhood is controlled by the <i>Radius Alpha</i> parameter and a larger value will result in a larger neighborhood.
			
			For more details see the <a href="http://www.inf.uni-konstanz.de/bioml2/publications/Papers2009/CeBe09.pdf">PBAC paper</a> by Cebron et. al.
			<br />
			If the node fails due to memory problems, this is usually due to a too large radius Alpha which results in many rows with a lot of neighbors.
		</intro>
		<option name="Column Selection">The columns that make up the vector space.</option>
		<option name="Radius Alpha">Radius Alpha parameter, influences the size of the
			neighborhood considered for the density estimation. A larger value corresponds to a larger neighborhood.
			Note that the node will issue a warning if any of the rows in the input table has more than 20% of the table in its neighborhood because this might
			indicate a too large <i>Radius Alpha</i> value.
		</option>
		<option name="Missing Value Handling">Missing values can't be used to build the model therefore two strategies exist to cope with missing values.
		The node can either fail if it encounters a missing value in one of the used columns or it can ignore the row in which the missing value occurred.
		Note that an ignored row is not part of the model and consequently the <b>Density Scorer</b> node will treat it as an unknown row.</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Data" index="0">Table to build a density model for.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Density Scorer Model" index="0">Density scorer model.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>