<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="graphdensityscorer.png" type="Learner"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Graph Density Initializer</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Creates a density model of a n-dimensional
		vector
		space, based on a kNN graph.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Creates a density model of a n-dimensional
			vector
			space, based on a kNN graph.
			The kNN graph is created by connecting each row with <i>k</i> rows closest (in terms of Euclidean distance) to it in the feature space (<i>k</i> is the specified number of neighbors).
			This way each row has at least <i>k</i> edges in the kNN graph, however there are two cases in which a row may have more than <i>k</i> edges:
			<ul>
				<li>It is among the <i>k</i> nearest neighbors of a row that is not among its own nearest neighbors.</li>
				<li>There are multiple rows that would be the <i>k</i>th nearest neighbor because they have the same distance to the row in question.</li>
			</ul>
			Each edge in the kNN graph is weighted using a Gaussian kernel over the distance of the connected rows with standard deviation <i>Sigma</i>.
			The density of a specific row is calculated as the mean weight of all its edge weights.
			For more details see the
			<a href="https://www.mpi-inf.mpg.de/fileadmin/inf/d2/Research_projects_files/EbertCVPR2012.pdf">RALF Paper</a> by Ebert et al.
		</intro>
		<option name="Column Selection"> The columns that make up the vector space.
		</option>
		<option name="Number of Neighbors">The number of neighbors which are considered.
		</option>
		<option name="Sigma">The Sigma for the Gaussian distance weighting function.
		</option>
		<option name="Missing Value Handling">Missing values can't be used to build the model therefore two strategies exist to cope with missing values.
		The node can either fail if it encounters a missing value in one of the used columns or it can ignore the row in which the missing value occurred.
		Note that an ignored row is not part of the model and consequently the <b>Density Scorer</b> node will treat it as an unknown row.</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Data" index="0">Table to build a density model for.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Density Scorer Model" index="0">A Density Scorer
			Model that can be used with the Density Scorer node.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>